Sumeet Shetty

SENIOR TECHNICAL ARCHITECT

Summary

A senior technical architect & software developer with close to 15 years of experience in application design, development and managing projects in all aspects of the software development lifecycle towards the delivery of successful business solutions. Having a strong communication, leadership and technical background.

Experience

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES (TCS)

•

Generali – Trieste, Italy

Technical Architect

- Requirement Gathering, Estimations, Functional & Technical Analysis.
- System Design, Development, Testing, Deployment.
- Designing & setting up micro services for foreign branches using Spring Boot.
- Setup build pipelines using Jenkins & infrastructure automation with Terraform.
- Swagger documentation of the microservices developed.
- Spring Batches.
- DB Integration Tests with Spring Boot and Test Containers.
- Junit, Integration tests with Mock Server.
- API Gateway & Multi pod setup for different regions.
- Splunk & Grafana for analytics & monitoring.
- Asciidoc & Confluence documentation.

Technical Architect

Oct 2013-Dec 2022

July 2008-present

Jan 2023-present

Intesa Sanpaolo – Milan, Italy

- Requirement Gathering, Estimations, Functional & Technical Analysis.
- System Design, Development, Testing, Deployment.
- Design & setup an environment of parallel development for developers from different teams.
- Coding the features, modules, interfacing with the different channels and the Core Banking systems.
- Breaking up a monolithic application into micro-services-based architecture to come up with loosely coupled, collaborating services.
- Process Improvements.
- Team Lead.
- Data Migration.
- Trade Finance product customization & rollout to 20 foreign branches.
- Diagrams to visualize Conceptual, Logical & Physical Data Models (Erwin) as part of defining an ETL pipeline b/w application & data warehouse.
- Rolling out new SWIFT messaging standards for LCs & GTEEs.
- Defining and mapping requirements for software development to streamline and automate business processes, and for software integration with payment services/bank and accounting software.
- Test Automation using Microfocus UFT & ALM.
- Documentation of the new features/architectures developed.

Contact

sumeetshetty.744@gmail.com

+39 3336285510

linkedin.com/in/sumeet-shetty

Skills

Java Microservices **Spring Boot** JavaScript Kubernetes Hibernate, JPA Gradle Maven React Terraform GIT Docker Junit/Mockito **Test Container** Spring AOP Swagger **Design Patterns Jenkins** Ascii Doc Google Cloud Solana **AWS Jenkins** Blockchain, DLT Swagger Erwin Apache CXF Splunk Jira Confluence UFT Liquibase

Certifications

Oracle Certified Professional Java Programmer
Google Cloud Platform – Associate Cloud Engr
Google Cloud Platform – Prof Cloud Architect
Certified Blockchain Solution Architect
CILS B1 Level Italian Language Certificate

Technical Lead

July 2012 - Sep 2013

ING Direct France - Paris, France

- Requirement Gathering, Estimations, Functional & Technical Analysis.
- System Design, Development, Testing, Deployment.
- Migration of existing business logic to a new framework and adding spring functionality.
- Complete redesign of legacy code base to develop Restful web services using Spring with the architecture team of ING DF. The business logic was exposed as Business Commands using MQ which had to be exposed as web services which in turn would be consumed by all the channels.
- Managing a team of 4 developers.

Java Developer

Jan 2009 - June 2012

ABN AMRO - Mumbai, India

- Technical Analysis, System Design, Development, Testing, Deployment.
- Built an interface for the SEPA payment application using REST APIs.
- Redesign a web application by adding new features to it. The mainframe backend had to be rewritten in Java using Hibernate.
- Created a new web application for a system built in PowerBuilder.
- Responsible for the maintenance and addition of new features to an existing credit & Risk management application.

Java Developer

July 2008 - Dec 2008

NSDL - Mumbai, India

- Development, Testing, Deployment.
- Responsible for the maintenance and addition of new features to an existing application.

Education

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING - 2008

SJCE, Mysore

Personal Skills

Problem Solving

Interpersonal skills

Strategic Planning

Quick Learner

Process Oriented

Languages

English	Hindi
Italian	Kannada
Sanskrit	Tulu